PERSONAL INFORMATION

Álvaro Enrich Carmona, +34 676 411 271, alvaroenrich@gmail.com, Barcelona.

ABOUT ME

I am an experienced FrontEnd developer with a background in Telecommunications engineering. I have worked in several types of companies, from startups to multinational companies. I have developed roles such as Full-Stack Engineer, Front End Tech Lead or FrontEnd Architect. In these roles, I have had to manage teams of up to six engineers, and have designed the FrontEnd architecture of applications in the banking or pharmaceutical industry.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FrontEnd Tech Lead at IDNEO Technologies

2022/01 - Present

Working for a Pharmaceutical company

- Frontend Tech & Team Lead
- Architectural decisions.
- MicroFE used for plugin architecture in FE. Pharmaceutical software has strong regulations that lead to long audits. Thus, the customer wants to be able to have a plugin-based software which enables them to add features without rebuilding the application. Also, this clearly splits code functionally and high-risk code (more strict audits there) is more isolated.
- Worked on a prenatal screening software with the plugin-based architecture using microfrontends with Angular 15+

Frontend Tech & Team Lead at Crealogix

2020/03 - 2022/01

Digital banking industry

Frontend Tech & Team Lead

2020/03 - 2021/07

- Responsible for FE part of the project, a digital banking mobile application for a bank in Saudi Arabia.
- Managing a team of up to 6 frontend developers.
- Architecture decisions related with the project
- Maintaining component libraries
- Maintaining functional (not UI related) libraries
- Angular 10 11 projects
- o Frontend Architect Architecture team

2021/07 - 2022/01

- Maintaining architecture libraries used by the project teams. (Angular 11)
- Giving technical support to project Tech Leads
- Improving performance of applications

- Technical interviews
- Involved in a SaaS Framework for Digital Banking development.

FrontEnd Tech Lead at TalentFY

2019/10 - 2020/03

Startup Environment

- Ownership of Angular 8 project
- o Refactors, Testing, Developing new functionalities
- Improving UX/UI of the platform
- o Improving platform performance, Improving the SEO of both page and blog
- Developing the company product, a tech recruiting marketplace.

Software Engineer at BuyYourself S.L.

2018/05 - 2019/10

Startup Environment

- Front End lead of two web-application projects developed using Angular 7 (An analytics dashboard and a buyer application), Responsive applications
- o Developing as Full-Stack. Integrating and developing APIs
- In charge of automated build pipelines

IT Consultant at Scytl Secure Electronic Voting S. A.

2016/07 - 2017/06

• Internship working on the sprint projects team.

EDUCATION

Master in Telecommunications Engineering

8.2, 2017-2019

University School ETSETB of the UPC (Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya)

- o Internship Innovation Project at ESADE (02/18 07/18) collaborating with FESTO
- Master final thesis: CASE STUDIO OF FRONT END TECHNOLOGIES TO DEVELOP SINGLE PAGE APPLICATIONS

Telecommunications Systems Engineering

7.0, 2013-2017

University School ETSETB of the UPC (Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya)

Recognition of outstanding academic achievement

LANGUAGES

- Catalan: C level. Native language.
- Spanish: C level. Native language.
- o English: C1 level.
 - o Certificate in Advanced English (CAE).

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Node.js, SCSS, Angular2+, TypeScript, Javascript.
- o Jest, Cypress
- o Kotlin, JUnit, Spring, MongoDB
- o Git, Jenkins, Bitbucket Pipelines (CI), Docker
- Agile Methodologies

INTERESTS

- o 3rd classified in the HackatH2On 2017.
- o Effort and self-learning ability. Result oriented and active problem solver
- Desire to keep learning
- Leadership ability, great listener and idea generator. Great teambuilder.